<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="resume.xsl"?>
<resume>
	<demographics>
		<name>Thomas Sullivan</name>
		<title>Software Developer</title>
		<address>Connecticut, United States</address>
    <!-- <link>https://sullivanscientific.com/</link> -->
		<email>sullivan.t@protonmail.com</email>
        <tagline>References available on request</tagline>
		<crypto>
			<fingerprint>EAB1 5D7C 7D16 EDB5</fingerprint>
            <key>https://keybase.io/thomassullivan/pgp_keys.asc?fingerprint=8d0b70ad4e0aa51c418dc1b9eab15d7c7d16edb5</key>
		</crypto>
        <picture>https://sullivant.github.io/images/bird-small.jpg</picture>
	</demographics>
	<keywords>
		<technologies title="Technologies">
            <tag>Linux</tag>
            <tag>windows</tag>
			<tag>git</tag>
			<tag>ETL</tag>
            <tag>Informatica Products</tag>
            <tag>ISO 13485:2016</tag>
            <tag>pipelines</tag>
            <tag>warehouses</tag>
            <tag>OMOP</tag>
            <tag>EPIC</tag>
            <tag>Clarity</tag>
            <tag>Hyperspace</tag>
            <tag>bash</tag>
            <tag>motion control</tag>
			<tag>perl</tag>
			<tag>java</tag>
      <tag>spring</tag>
      <tag>TCP/IP</tag>
      <tag>REST</tag>
            <tag>rust</tag>
            <tag>sql (ms, my*, oracle)</tag>
            <tag>IBM Netezza</tag>
            <tag>pipelines</tag>
            <tag>"Big" data</tag>
	    <tag>Medical Devices</tag>
      <tag>Splunk</tag>
		</technologies>
	</keywords>
    <experience>
        <company>
            <name>Protedyne</name>
            <link>http://www.protedyne.com</link>
			<icon>./icons/resuml.svg</icon>
            <role>
                <title>Software Engineer</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2019-09-16</start>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                    <tag>Java</tag>
                    <tag>Bash</tag>
                    <tag>SQL</tag>
                    <tag>Maven</tag>
                    <tag>SCM</tag>
                    <tag>Modbus</tag>
                    <tag>Embedded devices</tag>
                    <tag>Motion Control</tag>
                    <tag>Networking</tag>
                    <tag>Docker</tag>
                    <tag>Server administration</tag>
		    <tag>Splunk</tag>
                </tags>
                <description>
                      Embedded systems software engineer for a large laboratory setting that involves processing of multiple thousand patient samples per night across many dispirate systems.  These systems perform computations, sample handling, data processing, and analysis of patient samples in a manner that relies on efficiency, speed, and integrity to provide the best outcomes for the patient as possible. Involved in the internal audit preparation for ISO 13485:2016 across the organizational teams.  Works with other facets of the organization to provide application and process improvements, meet service level agreements, and troubleshoot issues.  Introduced and supported through to the production portion of a lifecycle, technologies such as docker and Splunk.                  </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                      Embedded java programmer / engineer with a focus on sample handling, motion control, and data analytics.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Provided technical support for systems and sales-staff when they were on-site.  Provided detailed instruction and documentation related to the proper update and troubleshooting of devices.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Worked with the embedded electronics developers and design teams in all phases of the project lifecycles, with attention to detail and discussion regarding new features, product lines, and developments.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                      Implemented systems to better review device logging in a cloud-based manner that allows for customer support and service to be able to proactively consider potential concerns with hardware and software as well as research and debug technical details.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                      Works with manufacturing and hardware engineering to create test, diagnostic, and bring-up software improvements for the products in all areas of their lifecycles.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
Develops core tools and technologies to provide expandable frameworks that meet our department's goals.  These frameworks have been vendor provided or home grown, depending on need, turn around time, and expandability.  
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
        </company>


        <company>
			<name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
			<link>https://vumc.org</link>
			<icon>./icons/victr.gif</icon>
            <role>
                <title>Application Developer</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2016-10-10</start>
                    <end>2019-09-16</end>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                    <tag>linux</tag>
                    <tag>git</tag>
                    <tag>ETL</tag>
                    <tag>Warehouses</tag>
                    <tag>ETL</tag>
                    <tag>OMOP</tag>
                    <tag>EPIC</tag>
                    <tag>Bash</tag>
                    <tag>SQL</tag>
                    <tag>IBM Netezza</tag>
                    <tag>EPIC</tag>
                    <tag>Clarity</tag>
                    <tag>Hyperspace</tag>
                </tags>
                <description>
                  Software application developer on a large scale translational research focused team, the Vanderbilt Institute for Clinical and Translational Research (VICTR).  This team is supported by the NIH, grants, and CTSA awards and provides data to research scientists in a multi-faceted approach.  Some of the tools produced by our team include the "BioVU" databank containing de-identified DNA information, healthcare data warehouses driven by clinical systems such as EPIC and Star, and user facing applications to help support principal investigators in the creation of grant funded research.
                </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                        Developed, maintained, and fine-tuned a large scale IBM Netezza database system that holds 60+ Tb of medical data in both identified and de-identified forms.  Work on this system involes attention to detail as the pipeline systems are designed to gather data from disparate source healthcare databases, files, and extracts and then normalize it into forms usable by the researchers and employees who generate phenotype/genotype cohorts.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Key developer in project mangement lead requests for eccentric and specific data "ETL" (Extract Transform Load) requests.  This often involves discussing and fully understanding source data systems, how they are accessed, translated, and will work with our target database schema (OMOP).   Always eager to learn new and intersting methods for improving both technical systems, but also the potential for process/workflow improvement at the employee level.  No stranger to visting departments and labs to better understand how the "machine" works.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Instrumental in the decision and implementation to source warehouse data from the newly installed EPIC Healthcare system (Clarity).  This required working with teams across the organization to understand how EPIC would be configured and how we, as a team, would have to react to these changes in order to maintain our steam stream of healthcare data to support research needs.  This included writing an application (Java) to extract needed tables from EPIC's Clarity database, shape the data, and load into our target Netezza system.  This process included attention to the speed at which we could extract data, with the final result being a multi-threaded Spring Boot java application, pipeline changes on the Linux servers, and working with a front-end team to design a dashboard to provide day-to-day system statistics (see below for detail).
                    </detail>
					<detail>
						Directly collaborate with product management and engineering/development team members to prioritize requests into the Assembla ticketing workflow via an impact assessment.
					</detail>
					<detail>
						Conduct sprint forecasting assessment in order to appropriately develop actionable and achievable project schedules.
					</detail>
                    <detail>
                        Developed threaded spring-boot java application to extract data from the EPIC Clarity (EHR) system and import into the target research Netezza system.  This involved discussion and planning with members of outside teams, on the Health IT side as well as systems support and security teams.  A specific challenge of this application was the amount of Clarity data there is to extract; our current needs involve roughly 200 source tables, some with over 500 million records.  Review and development of the application resulted in software that is threaded, involves reporting to a dashboard, and runs via multiple schedules, configured via control table.  The tables that extract on a daily basis (about 150) perform the entire extract process in under 45 minutes.  This is an improvement over the prior method of pulling data sequentially; the prior method took well over 3 hours per day.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Provides administration of source code repositories for our development team of 10+ members.  This involves repository mangement (location, security, backup) as well as insitituting a code review and merge request process and training developers who are new go the git ecosystem.
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
        </company>
        <company>
			<name>Hartford Healthcare Corporation</name>
			<link>https://hhchealth.org</link>
			<icon>./icons/hhc.jpg</icon>
            <role>
                <title>Application Architect</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2016-06-01</start>
                    <end>2016-10-09</end>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                    <tag>Informatica</tag>
                    <tag>PowerCenter</tag>
                    <tag>linux</tag>
                    <tag>git</tag>
                    <tag>ETL</tag>
                    <tag>Warehouses</tag>
                    <tag>sql-server</tag>
                    <tag>oracle</tag>
                    <tag>Sybase Transact SQL</tag>
                    <tag>git</tag>
                    <tag>EPIC</tag>
                    <tag>Clarity</tag>
                    <tag>Hyperspace</tag>
                </tags>
                <description>
                    Researched, developed, implemented, and supported large scale (10,000+ employee) ERP and medical interface systems. These projects involved multi-year timelines as well as integration with many different enterprise teams. Attended training for application and system level educational opportunities such as, EPIC Clarity Database, Informatica Administration and PowerCenter developer.
                </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                        Was lead architect on design of our legacy-to-new data migration needs (SmartStream to PeopleSoft). Designed and implemented an ETL driven, autonomous data collection process which allows for the creation of multiple data-marts that serve customer needs from finance to HR. This project required an understanding of customer needs, usage cases and histories, as well as an ability to imagine what the future business needs will be.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Included as key resource on the integration and interface portion of the EPIC migration project. This involved the creation of a framework of EPIC-to-Vendor connections through a Master File Transfer process that utilizes our B2B system. From creation of a file framework that allows for transfer of any type of necessary file to the logging, reporting, and notification systems, I was able to work on a team of peers to create a system-wide process and hand it off to the implementation teams. It is a critical portion of the EPIC healthcare system here at Hartford Healthcare.
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
            <role>
                <title>Senior Programmer / Analyst</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2007-02-01</start>
                    <end>2016-06-01</end>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                    <tag>SmartStream</tag>
                    <tag>Kronos</tag>
                    <tag>PERL</tag>
                    <tag>Bash</tag>
                    <tag>Linux</tag>
                    <tag>SQL Server</tag>
                    <tag>Sybase</tag>
                    <tag>Java</tag>
                </tags>
                <description>
                    Designed, supported, and implemented large scale EDW and Payroll/Financial warehouse systems and pipelines.  These projects provided analytical data and interfaces to the finance, payroll, and HR departments to be used in support of the business needs.  Included in these systems were support of Kronos, SmartStream, and homegrown timecard/payroll applications and databases.
                </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                        Continued development and life-cycle management of the intranet framework. Collaborated as a part of the non-clinical revenue cycle team developing top of the line interconnected and distributed systems. Using many languages such as Java, Perl, Ruby, SQL, (Oracle, Microsoft,and Sybase) as well as ETL systems such as Informatica (Developer II training included) to interface and provide data, metrics, and predictions to the business cycle teams.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Experience with "man in the middle" data migrations, interfaces, as well as solution generation/problem solving in patient critical systems.
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
        </company>
        <company>
            <name>Magnatech LLC</name>
            <link>https://magnatechllc.com</link>
			<icon>./icons/resuml.svg</icon>
            <role>
                <title>Software Engineer</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2004-07-01</start>
                    <end>2007-02-01</end>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                    <tag>C++</tag>
                    <tag>Bash</tag>
                    <tag>PERL</tag>
                    <tag>Embedded devices</tag>
                    <tag>Motion Control</tag>
                    <tag>Networking</tag>
                    <tag>Server administration</tag>
                </tags>
                <description>
                    Embedded motion control software development on systems utilized in harsh tube/pipe welding environments, network administration. Development in a team environment, including rabbit micro-controllers, hardware control with embedded systems, and user interface programming.
                </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                        Developed pendant/controller communication methods and protocols based on the TCP/IP standards.  This involved sourcing, configuring, and developing for a serial-to-ethernet device to communicate with the pendants i/o and ensure that serial data can be "pivoted" into proper packet lengths with enough command information to be reliably translated back from packet form into serial data on the controller to be read by the microcontroller there.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Continued work on PID tuning of the weld head systems to ensure the slight differences between what was requested in a button press on the pendant resulted in an acceptable physical action on the weld head.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Provided technical support for systems and sales-staff when they were on-site.  Provided detailed instruction and documentation related to the proper update and troubleshooting of devices.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Worked with the embedded electronics developers and design teams in all phases of the project lifecycles, with attention to detail and discussion regarding new features, product lines, and developments.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Administered the Windows and SQL based inventory systems, file shares, and backup solutions.
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
        </company>
        <company>
            <name>Winsted Volunteer Fire Department</name>
            <link>http://winstedfire.org</link>
            <icon>./icons/resuml.svg</icon>
            <role>
                <title>Firefighter</title>
                <tenure>
                    <start>2005-12-01</start>
                </tenure>
                <tags>
                </tags>
                <description>
                    Winsted Fire is a ISO Class 4 volunteer firefighting department that operates in the city of Winsted, Connecicut.  It has operated since the year 1862 and continues to provide fire suppression, rescue, emergency, and training services to the town and its surrounding area.
                </description>
                <details>
                    <detail>
                        Currently serving on the Winsted Volunteer Fire Department as both a firefighter and lieutenant officer.
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        Treasurer of the Aerial Ladder (tower) Company
                    </detail>
                    <detail>
                        AM lead person in charge of the "Junior" firefighter program, a Boy Scouts of America (BSA) provided service that allows children aged 14-17 to join and train as exterior firefighters, giving them valulable community service skills as well as an understanding of safety.  Many of these children have progressed to become full adult members of the department as well as paid full-time city departments in the area.
                    </detail>
                </details>
            </role>
        </company>
	</experience>
    <projects>
		<project>
            <name>VICTR - BioVU + Synthetic Deriverative</name>
			<date>2017-11-07</date>
			<link>https://victr.vanderbilt.edu/pub/biovu/</link>
			<icon>./icons/victr.gif</icon>
			<tags>
				<tag>Bash</tag>
				<tag>Java</tag>
				<tag>Linux</tag>
				<tag>Netezza</tag>
				<tag>ETL</tag>
				<tag>Research</tag>
			</tags>
			<description>
				BioVU is Vanderbilt's collection, or “bank,” of de-identified DNA samples. DNA is found in all of your cells and is what carries information from parents to children. Specific sections of DNA, called genes, control certain traits (like eye color) or may be involved in certain diseases. Researchers are using these samples to study the links between genes and disease and between genes and how a patient might respond to a prescribed medication.
			</description>
			<contribution>
				Designed and contributed to the implementation of a methodology to include EPIC's healthcare data as a source for the systems used to support the BioVU databank.  This included sourcing data from Clarity in a fashion that would allow for continued ingestion of patient data and demographics after the cutover from Star (legacy) to EPIC.
			</contribution>
		</project>
        <project>
            <name>Hobbies: Home Automation with Home Assistant and MQTT over z-wave/zigbee</name>
			<date>2018-01-01</date>
            <link>https://www.home-assistant.io/</link>
            <icon>./icons/resuml.svg</icon>
            <tags>
                <tag>automation</tag>
                <tag>networking</tag>
                <tag>zwave</tag>
                <tag>zibgee</tag>
                <tag>raspberry pi</tag>
                <tag>python</tag>
                <tag>wireless</tag>
            </tags>
            <description>
                A personal hobby project involved installing and updating a home automation system with a front-end dashboard.  This system allowed for control of standard devices like lights but also allowed for interaction via sensors such as door open/close and entry motion sensors.  Additionally, common activities like commuting traffic and weather patterns were included in a way that allowed for consistent and easy day-to-day usage; if rain was expected, a notice was sent via text or slack to my device.  When my device leaves the work area, it notifies myself and others of my expected commute time home.  Devices inside the house were configured to connect via z-wave or zibgee and provided data over small MQTT system messages.
            </description>
        </project>
        <project>
            <name>Hobbies: Open Source community involvement</name>
			<date>2019-01-01</date>
            <link>https://www.github.com/sullivant/</link>
            <icon>./icons/resuml.svg</icon>
            <tags>
                <tag>open source</tag>
                <tag>rust</tag>
                <tag>python</tag>
                <tag>C++</tag>
                <tag>ruby</tag>
            </tags>
            <description>
                In the open-source software I most often use (taskwarrior, cheat.sh, etc) I can be found submitting change and pull requests.  These changes and involvements are often focused around documentation updates and test cases, but have also been new features and bug fixes.
            </description>
        </project>
    </projects>
	<credits>
		<credit>
			<title>May the source be with you</title>
			<link>https://github.com/resuml/resuml.github.io</link>
			<icon>https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/logos_page/GitHub-Mark.png</icon>
		</credit>
	</credits>
</resume>
